

CONTACT

- **Q** 07 45 64 16 17
- ✓ rich.alan@proton.me
 https://alanrich.dev
- 56 Rue Riquet 31000, Toulouse France

COMPETENCIES

- Programming Languages
 - Javascript/Typescript
 - CSS
 - GraphQL
- Frameworks/Libraries
 - React
 - MUI
 - Redux
 - Next.js
- Testing & QA
 - Jest
 - Cypress E2E
- Development Tools
 - Nx
 - Git
 - NPM
 - Jenkins
- Architecture/System Design
 - Configuration-driven systems
 - Domain Object Modeling

LANGUAGES

- English (Maternal Language)
- Français (B1)

ALAN RICH

FRONT END DEVELOPER

PROFILE

As a front-end developer with five years of professional experience, I have worked extensively maintaining and debugging large-scale, configuration-driven systems. My recent role at Research Innovations Inc. involved resolving complex UI bugs within a framework powered by thousands of configuration files, demonstrating my ability to navigate highly abstracted systems. With an established record of remote work for U.S.-based companies in the national security sector, I bring adaptability, technical proficiency, and a self-driven attitude, capable of delivering results when the stakes are high and success is critical.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Innovations Inc.

2022 - 2024

Software Engineer II

- Used JS, TS, React & MUI to optimize front-end components, ensuring scalability and maintainability within a large Nx monorepo.
- Facilitated interaction between front-end components and underlying data models housed within domain-specific objects that encapsulated both data and business logic.
- Founded and lead a book club for Front End Devs to foster continuous growth and learning.
- Performed daily code reviews, always seeking opportunities to delete code.

OC Tanner

2021 - 2022

Software Engineer

- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to implement user-centric designs, ensuring a smooth and engaging experience for end users.
- Developed intuitive and responsive web interfaces using Javascript and React to optimize the user experience across various devices and screen sizes.
- Utilized GraphQL to efficiently fetch data from APIs, ensuring real-time, dynamic updates and improved performance.

Upwork

2019 - 2021

Freelance Web Developer

- Applied modern ES6+ features and React hooks to simplify state management, enhance reusability, and maintain clean, scalable codebases.
- Integrated RESTful API endpoints to dynamically render data, improving application efficiency and user engagement..

INTERESTS

- Pilates / Running
- Wild Camping
- · Russian, Indian, Greek Literature
- Classical Philosophy
- Burning Man
- Interrailing
- Neoclassical Art
- French Comedy
- Byzantine History

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

•	Technical Writer	Upwork	2015 - 2019
•	Research Assistant	Illinois Institute of Technology	2013 - 2014
•	Organic Chemist	Nestle (Chicago)	2012 - 2013

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Benedictine University

2004 - 2008

Thesis: "A One-Pot Asymmetric Robinson Annulation in the Organic Chemistry Majors Laboratory", *Journal of Chemical Education*, 85 (2008) 1531-1534, DOI:10.1021/ed085p1531

Cours de Civilisation Française de la Sorbonne

Language and French civilisation studies through a program administered by La Fondation Robert de Sorbon and charged with enhancing the influence of French civilisation throughout the world.

Illinois Institute of Technology

2013 - 2014

2009 - 2010

I was briefly enrolled in a doctoral program but decided that academic research was not my calling. During my studies, I performed genomic analysis of human colorectal cancer cells affected by microsatellite mutations in the $Bax\Delta 2$ gene.

Alliance Française de Toulouse

2023

Cours Intensif de Langue Niveau B1

PEER REVIEWED & INVITED PRESENTATIONS

Asymmetric Organocatalysis: Conjugate Addition Reactions & Robinson Annulations

2008

Science and Sociability Seminar, Benedictine University, Lisle Illinois

Synthesis of Organocatalysts for Asymmetric Robinson Annulations

2008

235th ACS Spring National Meeting Division of Chemical Education, New Orleans, Louisiana

Poster ID: 1163539

Asymmetric Catalysis in the Undergraduate Research and Teaching Curriculum

2007

233rd ACS Spring National Meeting Division of Chemical Education, Chicago, Illinois

Reactivity and Enantioselectivity of Chiral Imidazolidinone Organocatalysts in Asymmetric Robinson Annulations

2007

233rd ACS Spring National Meeting Division of Chemical Education, Chicago, Illinois
Poster ID: 659